Lenin Kumar Mohanty

E-mail: leninmohanty@gmail.com **Mobile:** +1 (512)-998-0868

Summary:

I am having total 13 years three months of experience in the software industry which I have spent for design, development, testing, integration, delivery and maintenance of software products. I have also managed multiple full scale projects for retail e-commerce domain.

Work Experience:

- 13+ years of work experience in IT industry.
- More than 5 years of experience in leading and managing projects of different domains (Mobile Commerce, Ecommerce, life science and pharmacy, NMS/EMS and telecom).
- Working as a Project lead for Cognizant Technology Solutions, Bangalore since June 2011 to till date.
- Worked as a senior system engineer for IBM India Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore since August 2009 to June 2011.
- Worked as a senior software engineer for Ness Technologies India Ltd, Bangalore since April'06 to July'09.
- Worked (Consultant) for **Motorola Electronics India Pvt. Ltd**. through Savvysoft Technologies Pvt. Ltd., **Bangalore**, as a Software Engineer since December'05 to April'06.
- Worked as Graphic Designer for Speedway Pictures Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore, since January 2001 to August 2005.

Professional Qualification:

Master in Computer Application (MCA).

Technical Skills:

Programming Skill : Java, J2EE (JSP, Servlets, JDBC), Spring, Struts-2

Websphere commerce, REST Service.

Server : Tomcat 5x, eWAS, WAS, WCS.

Web Tools : HTML, XML, XSL,Ajax, XPATH, JQuery.

Operating Systems : Windows, Linux, Solaris.
Database : Oracle, Sybase, MySql, DB2.

Other tools : Eclipse, Ant, Hibernate, Usablenet Lift Text, WCS.

Scripting : Javascript, Shell Script

<u>Achievements:</u>

- 1. Won Diamond in the rough from Cognizant for quickly learnt the project and leaded the team.
- 2. Got CZar of the month from Cognizant for the best contribution in the month of October 11.
- 3. Won The Perfectionist awards from Cognizant for my outstanding contribution towards the project and the organization.
- 4. SNAP award winner for excellent performance as project partner at NESS Technologies.
- 5. Quarterly award winner for excellent performance in the Ness Technologies.
- 6. Award winner for successfully completion in Ness for 3 years with excellent track record.
- Excellent feedback and appreciation from IBM Management for doing L3 development work of NETCOOL Webtop/ NGF.
- Received rainmaker award in WAG eCom Mobile project for outstanding contribution to the project and learning the niche technologies in very short span of time from Cognizant Technology Solutions.
- 9. Received Perfectionist award for great team work in WAG eCom Mobile for all the quality deliverables and releases from Cognizant Technology Solutions.

Project Experience Outline:

#1. The Home Depot (PIP/Product API)

Environment/Skills : Java/J2EE, REST service, Tomcat Grid, Design Patterns, Jersy API, Spring etc.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Working as a technical lead for the onsite Product API team of HomeDepot.
- Worked as an onsite contributor/coordinator for the project with coding, testing, integrating functionality and defects.
- Developed customized JUNIT framework for PIP and implemented the same, guided the offshore team to get acted on the same.
- Worked on PIP health check framework to fine tune it and deliver it as part of best performance practice.

#2. BassPro WCS Enhancements

Environment/Skills : IBM Websphere commerce, Javascript, Jquery, Java, J2EE

#3. Walgreens Ecommerce Mobile

Environment/Skills : xml,xsl,xpath,Java, Javascript, Html, DHTML, Jquery, Usablenet

#4. IBM Solution for Compliance in a Regulated Environment (SCORE)

Environment/Skills : Java, J2ee(Servlets, JSP), EMC Documentum, Adobe LCES, Web Services, Ant, JUnit, RAD, Clearcase, Websphear Application Server.

#5. CitiDirect Phoenix/Nextgen

Environment/Skills : Java, Swings, Applets, Hibernate, Spring, Web Services, Ant, Maven, JUnit, RAD, Clearcase, Websphear Application Server.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Extensively executed on the retail ecommerce projects for continuous release.
- Worked as a technical manager/lead for the team
- Played role of development coordinator/Scrum master
- Sprint planning, Story grooming, JIRA Board creation etc.
- Involved in code review, Design review and coding for specific modules.
- Involved in design, analysis, coding, testing, delivery and integration of new/existing tickets/enhancements.
- Mentoring junior members in the team.
- Involved in Code Review process and technical discussions.
- Communicate with the offshore counterpart with the project artifacts.
- Monitor and mentor Development and QA activities of offshore/onsite Dev and QA team.

#6. IBM TIVOLI Netcool Webtop

Environment/Skills : Java, J2EE(Servlets, JSP), Swings, Applets, Struts, Javascript, CGI, Security Manager, Object Server, Eclipse, Ant, Tomcat

#7. IBM TIVOLI Netcool GUI Foundation (NGF)

Environment/Skills :Jetspeed,Velocity,Java,J2ee(Jsp,Servlet),Eclipse,Ant,Apache

Role and Responsibilities:

Worked as a L3 developer for this product. These are some roles and responsibilities for the same:

- Leading the team of 4 members and assigning tasks to respective member.
- Worked for memory related issues (which comes from client where they encountered problems with large amount of threads occupying all the available memory and making the

application not to run) and analyzing them using different dump analyzer tools and solving them.

- Fixing complex bugs in specified time limit.
- Analyze the performance of the product using different tools (e.g. profiler) also to provide some solution using GC technique.
- Handling all the issues from the clients including the memory leaks and performance tuning
- Unit testing of all fixed issues
- Making monthly builds and intermediate requested builds
- Performance analysis using Netbeans Profiler and core dump analysis tool
- Handling all the issues from the clients
- Taking part of Integration of NGF into other products

#8. <u>Title</u> : Motorola Soft Switch CDMA (MSSC)

Environment/Skills : J2EE (Servlet), XML, XSL, XPATH, XQuery, Tomcat 5.0, Managed Object Server (MO Server), HTML, DHTML, Postgres-sql 7.2

Role and Responsibilities:

- As a Team member I am responsible for coding of servlet.
- Coding of client side page using HTML, XML and XSL.
- Coding of Client side validation and other functionalities using JavaScript.
- Unit testing of the codes.
- Fixing of bugs and testing them.